yalea.com 2018-07-17

# Privacy Policy | Yalea Languages

At Yalea we are aware of the importance you attach to the use of your personal information, and we therefore fully commit to complying with applicable international legislation, such as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the Data Protection Directive (95/46/EC), both of which are from the European Union. We appreciate the trust which you place in us to treat your data and information with due rigour and caution. 

This Privacy Policy presents the Data Processing Terms between Yalea and the users of all of its platforms and services, primarily the Yalea website, Yalea Newsletter, the Veintemundos and TeaTime-Mag magazines, the VocBox and VocDix learning tools, the online game and any other digital resource in which their customers, interested users and subscribers interact; setting out the terms by which Yalea uses and protects the information that is provided by users at the time they consent to the registration and processing of information. 

When visiting our website you will be consulted for your consent to the use of cookies. If you do not consent, cookies will not be recorded. This does not affect your ability to use the website and access any of Yalea's services. 

Notwithstanding, in order to request our language travel advisory services, you are required to provide your consent to providing personal data where it is required. By giving us your consent to the use of personal data you accept the terms described here, which imply that you are over 15 years of age and that you have read and understand the present conditions for the Processing of Data. 

Your response to the consent will be recorded with its respective date and time to show your preference and the moment in which it was collected. Your consent will expire if you expressly request an amendment or if Yalea deletes your personal information when the activities for which you have given your consent have been completed. For more details, please see Table 1. 

## What information do we collect and how do we use it?

The types of information which we collect each time you give your consent are described as follows. Table 1 (below) specifies each of the types of data which we collect, for what we use them, and the time for which we retain them on our servers without alteration. 

  * **Information you provide to us:** We receive and store all information that you enter in to the forms on our website or that you provide to us in any other way (chat, telephone, in person, etc.). 

  * **Automatic Information:** Whenever you interact with us digitally, we receive and store certain types of information. For example, like many other websites, we use cookies to collect information when your web browser accesses Yalea's web platforms. If you would like to read more about cookies and how we use them, please click here. 

It should be noted that all information recorded for data on language courses of interest, secondary data and cookies will be made anonymous once the data retention period has ended. The anonymization process allows information to be kept without the possibility of personally identifying individuals or reconstructing their profiles as the connection between this data and personal data is removed, therefore becoming only statistical data. 

In the event that you book a course to take a language trip with Yalea, you consent to the transfer of part of your data to the respective school(s) for the appropriate management of the course. While Yalea works with schools of high international standard, therefore meaning that all schools must comply with associated data protection regulations, we cannot guarantee that they will address the same issues contained in this document, as they have their own respective privacy policies and terms or conditions. Because of this, if you are interested or concerned, we suggest that you review the respective privacy policies of the schools you intend to travel to. 

In addition, it should be noted that if you subscribe to a Yalea newsletter or similar product, you will periodically receive the respective material via email. In the case that you do not subscribe to any of these products, we may send you occasional emails through our system, with special offers, new products or other advertising information that we consider relevant or that may provide some benefit to you. These emails will be sent to the address you provide and may be cancelled at any time (see Data Protection Rights section). 

## Data Protection Rights

The following actions can be requested at any time: 

  * To know, correct, update or request the deletion of your personal information, including restricting its processing or its portability. 

  * Cancel any marketing and product- or service-related communications that involve emails or notifications from Yalea. 

  * Change your consent to the collection, registration and processing of your personal data. 

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area you have the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your personal information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority. 

To request any of the above actions, please contact us directly at **dataprivacy@yalea.com**. 

If it is a matter which deals with the subscription to a product or service, it is sufficient to adjust your email subscriptions and notification preferences to which you are currently subscribed (TeaTime-Mag, Veinte Mundos, Yalea Newsletter, etc.). It is important to mention that in the case of clients it is essential to keep their personal information for at least 10 years due to accounting obligations. 

## Data control and security 

Yalea is highly committed to keeping your information secure, as such, we apply technical and organizational security measures to protect your stored personal data from inadvertent or deliberate manipulation, loss or destruction, as well as from access by unauthorized persons. 

In this context, we use advanced computer systems that are constantly updated with the aim of improving our security measures in line with technological changes. In this sense, we perform encrypted backups of the information stored on our servers on a daily basis for greater security. 

In the event of a security system failure or vulnerability involving a risk to your personal data, Yalea undertakes to notify the competent authority and the affected persons within 72 hours, together with details of the type of failure, the number of individuals potentially affected, the possible security consequences and the action plan to resolve them. 

Similarly, all Yalea employees are committed to this Privacy Policy, so that no individual or entity of the company may market, assign or distribute to third parties the personal information that is collected, except with your clear and prior consent or as required by a judge with a court order. 

Yalea SA, with address at Quellenweg 16, 6410 Goldau, Switzerland, will be responsible for monitoring all personal data you provide to us and therefore for your privacy in accordance with established laws. 

The Yalea website contains some links to other sites that may be of interest to you. Once you click on these links and leave our website, we no longer have control over the site to which you are redirected and Yalea is therefore not responsible for the terms or privacy and data protection of those other third party sites. These sites are subject to their own privacy policies and conditions for data processing, so please consult them to confirm that you agree with them. 

Without detriment to the above, it is important to note that all our suppliers and strategic allies that offer services involving data processing meet the requirements of the GDPR. Among these are Google and its associated tools, Mailchimp and LiveChat. 

Yalea reserves the right to change the content of the terms of this Privacy Policy at any time, which will be communicated promptly on our website and/or via email. 

Last updated: 24 May 2018.
